Prabhjot Singh Tugger

Full Stack Developer (8 Yrs. Expr.) https://www.linkedin.com/in/rickyharerri

Mob: +1 (647) 978-9947 Address: 4 Minister Rd. Brampton, ON L6P 0J9 Email: ricky_4567@yahoo.co.in

Professional Summary

Full Stack Web Developer using JavaScript and PHP frameworks/CMS's having 8 years of experience including creating, managing, designing and developing websites with the latest technologies and tools. Managing Projects including analysis of business requirements, creating documents in confluence, developing use cases and delivering key initiatives seeking an opportunity to use technical expertise to drive business goals and metrics. Experience in JIRA, Confluence, GitHub, AWS, EC2, Elastic beanstalk, AWS Amplify, RDS, Jenkins, Atlassian suite, Docker, FileZilla, and various server tools like Xampp, Wamp, Mamp. Also have experience in ReactJS, NodeJS, Core PHP, CMS WORDPRESS, MVC frameworks like Laravel, Codelgniter, RESTful API.

Envision making a mark and putting 100% efforts to grow not only as a Web-developer but also as a person.

Education

Bachelor of Engg & Tech. (CSE) from **Punjab Technical Uni**. **Jalandhar**, **India**, 2010 - 2013 Canadian Equivalency: Bachelor's degree (Four years)

Diploma in computer engineering from **PSBTE**, **Chandigarh India**, 2009 - 2010 Canadian Equivalency: Secondary school diploma and diploma (two years)

Technical Skills

Databases : MySQL, Mongo<u>DB</u>

Operating Systems : Linux, Windows, Mac OS

Languages : JavaScript, HTML5, CSS/CSS3 & PHP
Frameworks : ReactJS, NodeJS, Laravel, CodeIgniter

CMS : Wordpress, OpenCart

Others: Bootstrap, Material UI, Ant Design, SASS, RESTful API's, AWS, Twitter API's,

TypeScript

Tools & Applications: Docker, NetBeans IDE, Visual Studio Code, Sublime text, JIRA

Experience

Full Stack Developer at Zouk Design (Remote), Mohali, India, August 2021 - February 2022

Technology Used : ReactJS & NodeJS

Others : AWS, EC2, Elastic beanstalk, AWS Amplify, RDS

Responsibilities :

- Create RESTFUL APIs using Nodejs
- Implement designs in React templates
- Integration Backend API endpoints
- Work with AWS to build and deploy CI/CD pipelines
- Helping and managing team
- follow best practices in software development life cycle using the agile methodology.
- Troubleshoot, test and maintain the backend code and databases to ensure strong optimization, functionality and scalability.

Full Stack Developer at Bo-we ApS (Remote), Rønne, Denmark, May 2020 - July 2021

Technology Used : ReactJS & NodeJS

Others: Steam API, GCP, Elastic beanstalk, AWS Amplify, MongoDB

Project URL : https://leagues.gg/

Responsibilities :

- Create RESTFUL APIs using Nodejs
- Database design and maintenance using MongoDB
- Implement designs in React templates
- Integration Backend API endpoints
- Work Closely with testing team to manage project
- Integration with Steam API
- follow best practices in software development life cycle using the agile methodology.
- Troubleshoot, test and maintain the backend code and databases to ensure strong optimization, functionality and scalability.

Web Developer at Krescent IT Labs Pvt. Ltd. Chandigarh, IN, Mar 2017 - April 2020 Technology Used :ReactJS, Nodejs, PHP, MYSQL, RESTFUL APIs, Laravel, Wordpress,

Opencart

Responsibilities

- Managing and developing different features of the project using HTML, CSS, PHP, MYSQL, LARAVEL etc.
- Create RESTFUL APIs for the web and mobile team
- Develop new features and maintain existing features on backend system using PHP and MYSQL
- Collaborate with Product Manager and member of technical team to assess and implement new system requirements
- follow best practices in software development life cycle using the agile methodology.
- Troubleshoot, test and maintain the backend code and databases to ensure strong optimization, functionality and scalability.

Web Developer (PHP) at Wave Infotech, Chandigarh, IN, Jan 2014 - Mar 2017

Technology Used: PHP, Laravel, Wordpress

Responsibilities :

- Build websites using WORDPRESS.
- Write coding using HTML and CSS.
- Creating custom themes in WORDPRESS.
- Involved in the sprint planning, retrospective, technical discussions.
- Grooming on different Epic, Stories and tasks.
- Involved in different design sessions and strategies to accomplish the task.
- Scheduling and planning Epic and stories into sub-tasks.
- Analyzing the code and fixing bugs as per the coding standards.
- Database design and maintenance.

Interests

- Learning new things related to programming language.
- Reading books and novels
- Listening to Music

Languages: English, Hindi, Punjabi